University of Connecticut League Records 2002.0098
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut League Records
1966-2003
2002.0098
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
2.5 Linear feet
The collection contains documents related to the administrative, financial, social and cultural functions of the University of Connecticut League from 1966-1998. Founded "to promote social and friendly relations within, and to provide worthwhile service to the University and community," the UConn League has sponsored a variety of social, cultural, and fundraising events for the local and UConn communities and for its own membership.
University of Connecticut League
History
The University of Connecticut League, a civic organization organized to benefit members of the UConn community, held its first planning meeting in January, 1966, and continues to exist at the present time. Founded "to promote social and friendly relations within, and to provide worthwhile service to the University and community," the UConn League has sponsored a variety of social, cultural, and fundraising events for the local and UConn communities and for its own membership. Membership in the organization has depended on dues, which have been used to fund a membership directory, newsletter and student scholarships, welcome newcomers to the community, and fund community services selected by the UConn League.
The UConn League builds on a tradition of hospitality at the University of Connecticut, growing out of the Newcomers Club, which started in 1946. Organized around interest groups, special interests committees, and service groups, the UConn League has used a hierarchical system of governance which, although modified at certain points in its history, has included a board of directors, president, treasurer, and secretary. Events and fundraisers sponsored by the organization include formal dinners, bake sales, tag sales, cookbook sales, cooking demonstrations, a crafts festival, a fashion review, and shopping trips.
Scope and Content
The collection contains documents related to the administrative, financial, social and cultural functions of the University of Connecticut League from 1966-1998.
Organization
Series I: Administrative Records ( undated, 1966-1998 ) includes materials related to the governance of the organization, including the constitution, bylaws, organizational descriptions, contracts, job descriptions, manuals, committee reports, publicity materials, correspondence, minutes, and agendas. Minutes and Agendas include any financial records and correspondence mentioned therein, as they correspond to the business of the meetings.
Series II: Financial Records ( undated, 1968-1996 ) includes budgets, treasurer's reports and financial audits not corresponding directly to the business of UConn League board and general meetings, and administrative documents relating to the organization's finances.
Series III: Activities ( undated, 1968-1995 ) includes administrative and financial documents that relate to the planning, execution, and analysis of social and cultural fundraisers and events sponsored by the UConn League. The series also includes promotional materials and published reviews.
Series IV: 2006 Addition ( 1998-2003 ) includes administrative and finacial records accessioned in 2006.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials related to the history of the University of Connecticut's relational and associated organizations. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged topcially and alphabetically therein.
Separated Material
Publications have been removed from the collection for cataloging. Publications include The Notebook, Favorite Recipes (Dodd A5693) and At Your Fingertips: a Book of Services for Mansfield Seniors.
Newspapers have been photocopied and the originals disposed of.
Photographs have been separated and placed with like media.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated in installments by the president of the UConn League beginning in September 2002.
university of Connecticut League.; Administrative Records.; Advertisements.; Bylaws.; Community and College.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Histories.; Minutes.; Newsletters.; Newspapers.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Organizational records; Photocopies.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Publications.; Recipes.; Social Participation--Connecticut.; Typescripts.; Universities and Colleges--Public Services.; University Archives; Women in Community Organization--Connecticut.; Women in Community Organization--History--20th Century.
- Series I: Administrative Records, undated, 1966-1998
  - Barter Box Manual, undated (Box 4:, Folder 87)
  - Bylaws, 1970-ca. 1985 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Constitution, 1982-1985 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Contract-- Frank W. Ballard- UConn League Scholarship, ca. 1988 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Incoming, 1967-1993 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Internal, ca. 1989-1991 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Interest Groups, 1990-1991 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Job Descriptions, 1986-1987 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Mailing List, 1987 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Membership Characteristics, 1965-1968 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Membership Flyers, undated (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Minutes and Agendas
    - 1966 January - May (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - 1966 September - 1967 May (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - 1967 September - 1968 May (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - 1968 September - 1969 June (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - 1969 September - 1970 June (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - 1970 September - 1971 June (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - 1971 September - 1972 June (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - 1972 September - 1973 June (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - 1973 September - 1974 June (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - 1974 September - 1975 May (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - 1975 September - 1976 June (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - 1976 September - 1977 June (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - 1977 September - 1978 June (Box 2:, Folder 23)
    - 1978 September - 1979 June (Box 2:, Folder 24)
    - 1979 September - 1980 June (Box 2:, Folder 25)
    - 1980 September - 1981 June (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - 1981 September - 1982 June (Box 2:, Folder 27)
    - 1982 September - 1983 June (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - 1983 September - 1984 May (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - 1984 September - 1985 June (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - 1985 September - 1986 June (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - 1986 September -1987 May (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - 1987 September - 1988 May (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - 1988 September - 1989 May (Box 2:, Folder 34)
    - 1989 September - 1990 June (Box 2:, Folder 35)
    - 1990 September - 1991 June (Box 2:, Folder 36)
    - 1991 September - 1992 June (Box 2:, Folder 37)
    - 1992 October - 1993 May (Box 2:, Folder 38)
    - 1993 October - 1994 June (Box 2:, Folder 39)
    - 1994 September - 1995 May (Box 3:, Folder 40)
    - 1995 September - 1996 June (Box 3:, Folder 41)
    - 1996 September - 1997 June (Box 3:, Folder 42)
    - 1997 September - 1998 May (Box 3:, Folder 43)
  - News Clippings and Press Releases, 1984-1991 (Box 3:, Folder 44)
  - Notebook Committee Report, ca. 1990-1991 (Box 3:, Folder 45)
  - Notes for League History, 1966-1991 (Box 3:, Folder 46)
  - Organization Description, undated (Box 3:, Folder 47)
  - Service Research Committee Reports, 1980-1991 (Box 3:, Folder 48)
  - The Notebook drafts and correspondence, 1984-1994 (Box 3:, Folder 49)
  - UConn League Flyers, 1992-1999 (Box 3:, Folder 50)
  - UConn League Log, 1991 (Box 3:, Folder 51)
  - Unidentified Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 52)
  - Volunteer Committee Agenda, 1988 (Box 3:, Folder 53)
  - Ways and Means Committee, 1980-1985 (Box 3:, Folder 54)
- Series II: Financial Records, undated, 1968-1996
  - Annual Treasurer's Reports, 1970-ca. 1994 (Box 3:, Folder 55)
  - Honesty Bonds, 1969-1970 (Box 3:, Folder 57)
  - Invoices, 1986-1995 (Box 3:, Folder 58)
  - Monthly Treasurer's Reports, 1968-1996 (Box 3:, Folder 59)
    - Financial Audits, 1968-1994 (Box 3:, Folder 56)
  - Proposed Budgets, 1975-1996 (Box 3:, Folder 60)
- Series III: Activities, undated, 1968-1995
  - Academic Colloquy, 1968-1969 (Box 3:, Folder 61)
  - Hospitality, 1968-1988 (Box 3:, Folder 62)
  - Mansfield Training School Project, ca. 1976-1977 (Box 3:, Folder 63)
  - Trouping Theatre, 1978-1985 (Box 3:, Folder 64)
  - Festival, 1984 (Box 3:, Folder 65)
  - Evening in Black and White, Correspondence, Reports, Notes, 1985 (Box 3:, Folder 66)
  - Evening in Black and White, Promotional Materials, News Clippings, Invoices and Receipts, 1985 (Box 3:, Folder 67)
  - Tag Sale, 1985 (Box 3:, Folder 68)
  - Birthdays to Go, 1985-1986 (Box 3:, Folder 69)
  - Crystal Mall Shopping Trip, 1986 (Box 4:, Folder 70)
  - Spring Fling, 1986 (Box 4:, Folder 71)
  - Bake Sale, 1987 (Box 4:, Folder 72)
  - Skate for Scholarship, 1987 (Box 4:, Folder 73)
  - Masquerade, 1988 (Box 4:, Folder 74)
  - Poinsettia Delivery, 1988 (Box 4:, Folder 75)
  - Holiday Open House Supper, 1988 (Box 4:, Folder 76)
  - Master Recipes, 1989 (Box 4:, Folder 77)
  - Fashion Review, 1990 (Box 4:, Folder 78)
  - Gala Non-Event, 1990 (Box 4:, Folder 79)
  - The Royal Slave, 1990 (Box 4:, Folder 80)
  - Know Your Town Fair, 1990-1995 (Box 4:, Folder 81)
  - Favorite Recipes II Cookbook, 1991 (Box 4:, Folder 82)
  - Stockbridge Trip, 1991 (Box 4:, Folder 83)
  - 25th Anniversary Celebration, 1991 (Box 4:, Folder 84)
  - Bridge Marathon Fundraiser, 1994 (Box 4:, Folder 85)
  - UConn League Tote Bag, undated (Box 4:, Folder 86)
- Series IV: 2006 Addition, 1998-2003 (Box 4:)
  Scope and Contents note
  Administrative records, financial records.
- Series V: Theater Productions (2012 Addition), undated, 1964-1982
  - Brave Little Tailor, undated (Box 5)
  - Brave Little Tailor, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - Androcles and the Lion, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Silver Whistle, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Uniform Unicorn, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Greensleeves Magic, 1978 (Box 5)
  - In One Basket, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Out of the Bag, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Gabriel Ghost, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Granny's Grand Adventure, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Six or Seven, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Round and Arounc, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Fortune Teller, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Clippings and cards, undatged, 1964-1979 (Box 6)
  - Clippings and cards, undated, 1976-1982 (Box 6)
  - Photographs, 1964-1982 (Box 6)
  - Poster, undated (Box 6)
  - Theater productions, undated (Box 6)